A Inventory of the Asian Pictorial Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Asian Pictorial Collection
1883-2005
XX771
1 manuscript box, 1 oversize box, 1 album box, 8 envelopes, 1 oversize folder (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Photographs, drawings, and paintings, depicting miscellaneous scenes and personalities in Asia, including scenes of revolutionary disturbances in Iran, ca. 1908.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in Stanford University's online catalog.
Subjects
Asia--Pictorial works.; Iran--History--1905-1911--Pictorial works.
Container List
- 1 album containing 16 prints taken during the Persian revolution of 1908. (File fA)
- 1 print of a selamlik (sort of Trooping of the Colour, the weekly public procession of the Ottoman Sultan to the mosque for the Friday noon prayers of Sultan Abdul Hamid II, Constantinople, 1908; 1 print depicting Ibn Saud, King of Saudi Arabia, and Abdullah Alireza, Governor of Jiddah, meeting in Raghama, near Jiddah, in late 1925 or early 1926 to negotiate the surrender of iddah; and 1 print depicting Trebizond, Turkey, in the early 1900s; 1 drawing of a procession in Korea. (File m*B)
- 1 print of General Etterg, commandant of the city of Adrianopol during the war of 1877-1878 (present day city of Edirne, in Turkey). (File C)
- 3 prints of the visit of Prince Faisal of Saudi Arabia to the Hoover Institution in 1945. (File D)
- 5 negatives of oriental screens. (File E)
- 1 print of the first Korean diplomatic mission to the U.S., 1883. (File mF)
  Caption in Korean and English.
- 2 prints pertaining to Election Day, May 1948, in Korea. (File G)
- 1 print and 1 negative of R. Turnbull, American officer, somewhere in Asia, probably after World War II. (File H)
- 10 prints depicting the cities of Cairo, Mecca, Damascus, and Jerusalem, and people of Palestine, late 1800s-early 1900s. (File mI)
- 5 prints of street scenes in Damascus, Syria, showing posters of President Hafez Assad, 1993. (File J)